Elijah Raffo

Portland, OR 97224

(971) 275-7057 eliraffo@gmail.com

<u>linkedin.com/in/eliraffo</u> eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Project manager and data analyst with a passion for delivering business impact within a fast-paced environment. Demonstrated experience in building and leading a team, analyzing large datasets, and modelling complex business operations. Skilled in critical thinking and problem solving.

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate in Business Intelligence & Analytics • Portland State University

Post-Bacc. Focus in: Mathematics & Statistics

Concepts: Data Visualization & Dashboards • Prescriptive Analytics (Linear Optimization, OCCAM) • Data Mining & Predictive Modelling

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration • University of Oregon

Major Concentration • Operations and Business Analytics

Minor • Computer Information Technology

Concepts: Database Mgmt. ● Predictive Analytics ● Descriptive Analytics ● Supply Chain Mgmt. ● Business Strategy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program Manager

Lam Research Corporation • Portland, OR

Sept. 2019 - Current

Oct. 2019 - June 2020

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 3.93 / 4.0

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

<u>Managed</u> programs focused on metal deposition which over 7-months fought for new market share by hitting aggressive cost targets, technical requirements, and customer timelines:

- Led multiple programs and projects through the development process (PDR) to meet business objectives and timelines requirements.
- Implemented new technology and BoM cost reduction by working a cross-functionally areas from Eng., Supply Chain, and Manufacturing.
- Coordinated mitigations strategies and communicated program risks and KPI's to Stakeholders and Executives.

Assessed the validity of manufacturing (ACU) charges, and over 12-months generated a reduction of ≥\$1M in charges to the PECVD product group.

Demonstrated quantitatively the connection between manufacturing efficiency and the implementation of POA BOM structuring.

Operations Analyst

Lane Forest Products, Inc. • Eugene, OR

June 2018 - June 2019

Quantified the efficiency of the Delivery Department by developing and applying a cost model within 3-months. Implemented a delivery pricing structure which identified and stopped losses on and increased profit on delivery by an estimated \$36,000 per year.

- Utilized visualization to explain the profit margin of all order combinations (~50K combinations) to stakeholders.
- Created and instituted a spreadsheet which uses a Google Distance API to automate and optimize the delivery price quoted to customers.

<u>Automated</u> a logistic reload which over 6-months moved 55,000 tons of material, resulting in becoming the customer's primary service provider. <u>Managed</u> the export of international orders by developing process mapping, managing documentation, and coordinating the flow of materials.

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company • Portland, OR

June 2017 - Sept. 2017

Redesigned the company's Point-of-Sale interface for all Eugene Teahouse locations which:

• Improved storefront efficiency and created data which could depict customer preferences, inventory levels, and automate reorder points.

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

1 to 2 Years SAP ● Python (Pandas, NumPy) ● R (ggplot, lessR) ● JavaScript (RESTful API's, Node.js, React.js)

2 to 4 Years Business Intelligence (Power BI, DAX, Tableau) ● SQL (Access, MySQL) ● MS Excel (Power Pivot, Dashboards, VBA) ● Linear Optimization (ompR, Solver) ● MS Office (MS Timeline, Teams, OneNote, Visio, Outlook, Projects, PowerPoint, Word)

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATION

Lane Forest - Delivery Analysis	Townshend's - POS Redesign	Power BI vs. Tableau vs. R	Linear Optimization in R
Operational analysis delivering	Automating operations, and	A comparison between the above	Modelling business scenarios, and
impact with visualization	creating a valuable data pipeline	platforms ability to visualize	creating actionable information

Certified Associate in Project Management (PMI) • Lean Six Sigma Green Belt (SSGI) • Scrum Master (SSGI)

Data Science A-Z (Udemy) • Power BI (Udemy) • Tableau (Udemy) • Certificate of Outdoor Leadership (OPP)

http://eliraffo.github.io/ (All projects and certifications can be viewed on GitHub)